{
    "id": "b12f5d1810864e2397ea01086e6027c5",
    "title": "Subordinating Conjunctions",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I don’t know …………………… he is innocent.",
            "description": "We use whether to introduce indirect yes/no questions.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "weather",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "635787f4e2684e48ad4991ed0749eb99"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. she will come I am not sure at the moment.",
            "description": "When an indirect question is fronted, we use whether, not if.",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "That"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "06c0e71a1b2048e086f5b9ad85d9c6c6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked …………………….. she had met me before.",
            "description": "Both whether and if can be used to introduce indirect yes/no questions.",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c5a8b406d2cf496d8a167328ce3491fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the closet ………………………. she keeps her things.",
            "description": "We need a place word here.",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2f85a0f8ca43449fbd2f71a0f500e789"
        },
        {
            "question": "The consequence of his stupidity was ……………………….. he soon lost his money.",
            "description": "That is merely a connector. When we split the sentence into two clauses, we get:\r\nHe soon lost his money.\r\nIt was the consequence of his stupidity.\r\nWe can combine them with that.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c0131f87ea66459b97c748a9cf883413"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is beautiful. She is equally intelligent. That means she is as beautiful as ………………..",
            "description": "Both clauses have the same pattern in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "intelligent",
                "is intelligent",
                "she is intelligent"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d2f18aba3b5543929d63be32226c51c2"
        },
        {
            "question": "A cottager and his wife had a hen …………………….. laid a golden egg every day.",
            "description": "Both that and which can be used to refer to animals, birds or things.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e08383eb56cd4f98a2cdda9a36fb1876"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ran so quickly ……………………… he soon overtook me.",
            "description": "The conjunction so…that… is used to indicate ideas such as effect or purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "when",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "751379183cdd4fa5a5bef196aef1be15"
        },
        {
            "question": "He spoke in ……………………… a low voice that nobody could hear him.",
            "description": "We use such before 'adjective + noun'. ",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "such"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a848f6ac5730429db7f91745ec3834c4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tell me what …………………………. done?",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the auxiliary verb goes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "have you",
                "you have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "11dd8af82ca34099a4083d121486ddef"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. you are drunk aggravates your offence.",
            "description": "That-clauses are not normally used alone as subjects. They are often introduced by the expression ‘the fact’.",
            "answers": [
                "Fact",
                "The fact",
                "The fact that"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9300b5a816514d50a17e4dd6184a732e"
        },
        {
            "question": "They paid no attention to ………………………. she was depressed.",
            "description": "That-clauses after prepositions are introduced by ‘the fact’.",
            "answers": [
                "fact",
                "fact that",
                "the fact that"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "56fb36b51c194ccb81fc72f674b9701f"
        }
    ]
}